Sebastien !
Sebastien ?
Miss Linh .
Come this way .
Sit down .
I 'm Officer Guy Baron . This is Officer Bao .
Do we need a interpreter ?
I can understand you .
What is your name and your duty at Sa-Cat estate ?
My name is Linh .
I 'm a housemaid at Sa-Cat plantation .
" As you know , . "
Captain Sebastien Laurent was murdered
last night in his bedroom .
We 're questioning all involved .
There 's been a string of murders committed around the area .
We know you discovered the captain 's body
and you 're shaken up . We need your help .
Can you answer some questions ?
How long have you been in Sa-Cat ?
Speak !
I came to Sa-Cat from a small village in the countryside .
I was searching for work .
There weren 't many jobs where I was from .
Much of the countryside was destroyed by the bombings .
What do you want ?
I heard that there 's a need for a housemaid at the estate .
You may call me â € œMrs . Han . "
Mrs. Han .
How do you know of this place ?
From the people at the market .
Then you know of Sa-Cat 's history .
I 'm not from around here .
Thank you .
Have you been a servant at an estate before ?
No . Not yet .
I 've done housework with my mother on the farm .
Sa-Cat is run like a French estate .
Not like a Vietnamese one .
Of course .
Where is your family ?
My family ...
they were all killed during an air raid .
Our farm is gone too .
You have no family members at all ?
No home ?
You walked all the way here from your village ?
Yes .
How far is that ?
About forty kilometers .
Mrs. Han ,
I need a job .
I need a place to live .
This is the only job opening for miles around .
You can stay here .
I 'm only hiring you on a trial basis .
If you work hard , you can stay .
But if you 're a burden
and the food you eat costs more than your worth ,
you will need to find another place .
Is that clear ?
Yes , Ma 'am .
I won 't disappoint you .
You can wear these .
Get yourself acquainted with the manor .
We 'll start tomorrow .
Thank you .
You 're getting blood on the floor .
Sorry .
Here 's some medicine I 've made .
Medicine you 've " made " ?
I practice Eastern medicines and remedies .
Besides being the cook ,
I 'm a herbalist ...
a witch .
Mrs. Han says there are only a few servants in the house .
That 's right .
Just me , Mrs. Han and the groundskeeper , Mr. Chau .
Why doesn 't the Captain hire more servants ?
Most servants won 't work here .
Why not ?
Stupid girl !
You don 't know what you 've gotten yourself into .
I don 't understand .
Sa-Cat is a place of death .
Hundreds of people have died here on the plantation .
The Vietnamese workers used to be violently abused by the French overseers ,
when it was a functioning plantation .
The French recruited from all over the country .
Lied to them about the promise of a good wage and home .
When the poor workers got here ...
What happened to them ?
Workers were whipped to death .
Women were violated .
Children were torn from their families .
Hundreds of bodies lay buried beneath those rubber trees without gravestones .
Many claim that the plantation was fertilized
by the bodies of these workers .
There are many spirits ...
roaming those woods .
Spirits ?
I thought I heard something earlier .
You heard the crying , right ?
Who is it ?
Captain Laurent once had a wife , Madame Camille ,
and a child who lived at this estate .
While he was away at war ,
Madame Camille went mad with loneliness waiting for the Captain to return .
She never liked Vietnam , which made her insane .
Until one day ,
as she was bathing the baby ,
she drowned him in the tub .
Madame Camille kept the dead baby
until it rotted and decayed .
Realizing what she had done and consumed with grief ,
she took their dead son to the lake ...
and drowned herself .
You are afraid of ghosts , aren 't you ?
My mother said there is no such thing as ghosts .
Oh , they exist .
Ghosts exist .
You start with the windows .
Never look at the Captain or his guests in the eyes .
You must show your obedience and servitude .
Always get the freshest produce .
Even a day old isn 't good enough .
And most importantly ...
it 's forbidden to speak of Lady Camille and Captain Laurent 's child .
Understood ?
I understand .
Mr. Chau .
This is Linh .
She will be working for us as a housemaid if things work out .
How do you do ?
Nice to meet you .
If you run out of wood , Mr. Chau can help you .
On the colder evenings ,
Captain Laurent likes fireplaces because they remind him of his childhood .
Thank you but I think I can manage it .
Mr. Chau doesn 't live in the manor
but in the shacks close to the plantation trees .
Is Mrs. Han working you too hard ?
Not at all .
What 's happening ?
It happens occasionally .
Power should be back up in the morning .
We are in a war , after all .
Are you afraid ?
No , Ma 'am .
Good night .
What happened ?
Captain Laurent !
What ? Captain Laurent !
He 's been shot !
Bring him inside immediately .
Quickly !
Watch your step , Sir .
Sebastien , Fighting !
Mrs Han , Hold him steady .
I almost have the bullet .
We need more morphine .
I will take the bullet out .
Sebastien !
Please ...
We need to give him Eastern medicine .
He won 't survive without it .
You know that his family forbids it .
Western doctors know nothing of these matters of survival .
This is not your decision to make .
I am the housekeeper .
He 'll die before morning !
Stop .
I forbid you to go in there .
I forbid you from leaving the servants quarters
until he is well again .
If he dies ,
you will have Madame Camille to answer to .
Are you making breakfast ?
Take Captain Laurent 's breakfast up to his room .
By myself ?
Stupid girl .
I 've been banished from his living quarters .
You 'll have to do it .
Hurry !
Who are you ? Why are you here ?
Get out of my home ! Get out !
I 'm sorry .
There 's been an emergency in my family .
I 'll need to leave Sa-Cat for a few weeks .
My mother is gravely ill
and I need to travel to Saigon to visit her before she ...
How long will you be gone ?
I don 't know .
Linh .
Yes , Ma 'am .
You will be in charge of taking care of Captain Laurent .
Mrs. Han ,
she doesn 't have the experience to do that .
I don 't know if I could do this alone .
It 's an order .
Work faster !
No talking !
Do you hear me ?
Remember not to put the tree bark down .
You two !
Sir ! Sir !
She didn 't know !
It 's my first time , sir !
Please , sir !
You two .
You know how much that sap is worth ?
More than both of you combined !
Sir , please forgive her .
Sir ! Please , sir !
Hold her down !
It 's my first time ! I didn 't know !
Put your hand out !
Back to work !
Linh , wake up !
The Captain 's gotten worse .
What 's happened ?
He has an infection and a high fever .
He 'll need a doctor .
Who are you going to get at this hour ?
What are you doing ?
Mrs. Han forbids it .
But what if he dies while on your watch ?
The Western medicine hasn 't worked .
I made a promise to Mrs. Han .
He could die any second now !
Do you want to be responsible for his death ?
Don 't stop me .
Captain , drink some of this .
What do we do now ?
It 's not working .
Were you here last night ?
Yes , captain .
I just saw flashes of what happened .
Thought I saw your face .
Mrs. Ngo is the one you should thank .
You speak well .
Not really .
How did you learn ?
My aunt was a school teacher .
She taught me and my brother .
It 's nice to have someone else in the house
who understands me .
We need to clean your wound ..
... from the infection .
I need to bathe you .
How long have you been here ?
Just a couple of weeks , captain .
Do you like it so far ?
Yes , captain .
Pass me my scotch .
I 'm sorry .
Those damn revolutionaries .
Got me in an ambush on my way home .
I 'm glad you survived it .
You saw her , didn 't you ?
Who ?
Madame Camille .
Will you show her to me ?
I can 't show you .
The Captain forbids it .
It 's been many years since anyone 's been in this room .
What did you see ?
A woman in a black dress .
Madame Camille . She never smiled .
These are the very last photos of her .
Captain Laurent ?
When he was about seventeen .
He was already in charge of the plantation 's operations .
And that 's Mrs. Han .
She started working at the estate as an interpreter
before becoming the head housekeeper .
You know ,
they never found Madame Camille 's body .
The police dredged through the whole lake for a week .
They couldn 't find anything ...
The captain has an emergency meeting with some high-ranking officers .
Did you know they were coming ?
If I 'd had known , I would have prepared .
Don 't just stand there . Help me .
I have feeling that Giap will want
to confront us should we go
into Dien Vien Phu .
And they will be prepared .
How do you know this ?
They almost got me on my way home .
I just think we shouldn 't get
too confident .
Tides of war are turning against us .
What do you mean , Laurent ?
I mean they 've become wise to us .
We didn 't think that a small group
of rubber workers were going to make
much of a difference in 30 's .
And it resulted in a revolution
that forced us plantation owners
to make concessions .
Let 's not underestimate them .
I 've been watching you .
I see you looking at me too , right ?
No , I don 't . No , I don 't .
I know you want a big French man like me , yeah ?
- Come on . - No , no , please .
Leave me alone . No !
- You will like it . - No !
Please ! No ! Please .
Leave me alone .
No !
You ..
You think you can hurt me ?
No !
You deserve it , you god ..
Get off of her .
Sebastien , wait , wait !
- Wait ! - Get the hell out of my house .
Are you okay ?
How long will you and Mr. Chau be away ?
About a week .
Through the New Year .
I don 't know where Mr. Chau will go for Tet this year .
And you will see your family in Hoa Binh ?
I 'd invite you
but you 'd be too busy being head of the household .
What do you mean ?
Now that Mrs. Han left you all this responsibility ,
you can 't just leave , can you ?
I suppose not .
Linh ?
You have the whole week off .
I know .
I 'm looking for my schedule .
I 'll get it for you .
- Oh . - I 'm sorry .
No . Don 't worry . It 's just old files .
Who are these people ?
All the workers .
Every single one of them .
From the very beginning of the plantation .
Your schedule .
Happy New Year .
Happy day to you too .
What 's wrong ?
Holidays are difficult for me sometimes .
Me too .
Hello !
Help me , I 'm lost !
Mister !
Let me go !
It 's me . It 's just me .
Good morning .
How did I get here ?
I put you there .
I slept on the couch .
But , captain ..
You don 't need to call me captain .
You can call me Sebastien .
I 'm going out for a drive .
Would you care to join me ?
Get in .
- I 'm sorry . I 'm sorry . - Keep going . Keep going .
I 'm breaking your car .
- It 's okay . - I 'm sorry .
Ong Chau will fix it .
- Let me . - Okay .
How 's your family , Aunt Ngo ?
How are your family ?
They are doing well , Captain .
Good .
Did you see your children ?
I don 't have children anymore . My son died years ago .
I didn 't know that .
After all these years .
Is there anything else you 'd like , Captain ?
Yes . There is .
Linh .
Sit and eat with me .
Sit .
I invite you to eat with me .
Please eat .
What are you doing here ?
I went to get firewood .
Let me see .
I 'm okay .
Where are we ?
Years ago ...
the overseers ,
they used this place
to imprison runaway workers .
They 'd shackle them here ,
and leave them here for days .
Finally ...
many of them would starve to death .
How do you know so much about this ?
I was an overseer .
You ?
But they were people like you and me .
Wrong !
To me ,
they were unappreciative ingrates .
Stay away from me .
Have her take them up to the bedroom .
Why didn 't you write to me
to let me know you were coming ?
I wanted to surprise you .
But what if I weren 't here ?
You would have traveled all this way
for nothing .
I wouldn 't say for nothing .
I 'd have just stayed here until you returned .
Besides , I 've missed it here .
Madeleine , I distinctly remember
you calling Vietnam wretched .
You ran back to France
as quickly as possible
after your family sold their plantation .
It 's no secret I was homesick .
I missed Paris as much as I missed you , my darling .
Didn 't you miss me ?
Of course .
You could have given me some notice .
Can 't I come and see my fiancÃ ©
whenever I please ?
So , you 're Sebastien 's maid ?
Yes , mademoiselle .
Has he been faithful ?
Sorry ?
Has Sebastien been faithful to me ?
I wouldn 't know , mademoiselle .
Yes , you would .
You 're here the whole time .
I don 't know .
I don 't think he 'd cheat on me .
I can 't imagine him falling for a crude local .
I guess you 'll do .
Pardon me ?
You are to be my chambermaid
when I live here .
I don 't understand .
Well , Sebastien is obviously
not coming back to Paris
with my family fortune dwindling
I 'm gonna have to live in this horrible place .
But I thought that the Laurent family was the one ...
You were eavesdropping .
It 's okay .
You were in the same room .
Besides , we 're gonna have to get to know
each other if you are gonna be my servant .
A woman needs to do things
to secure her future sometimes .
Take my advice .
You 'll need to learn that to survive .
Thank you .
Do you have marmalade ?
She couldn 't find any at the market .
And she has no time to make it , mademoiselle .
Well , I suppose the service here
isn 't as good as it is in Paris .
Thank you , Mrs. Ngo .
Perhaps this afternoon , you can show me
the new rose garden .
Sure .
What are you doing in here ?
I was just cleaning .
Why are you crying ?
I 'm not crying .
Mademoiselle .
I 'm missing my bracelet .
What have you done with it ?
I haven 't seen your brace ...
It was here on the night stand
and now it 's disappeared .
I 'm sorry but ...
I distinctly remember seeing it there
before we went down to breakfast .
I 'm sorry but I do not know
where your bracelet is .
Sebastien , you 're not listening to me .
But it doesn 't mean that she stole it .
I 've seen this before .
My maid was stealing from us for years
and by the time we found out
it was too late , she 'd sold everything .
You are jumping to conclusions .
She 's the only one that could 've been in my room .
I know it was her .
Mademoiselle .
- Please , mademoiselle . - What are you doing ?
I know she has it .
Madeleine , stop !
Now do you believe me ?
But I didn 't take it .
These servants steal from us all the time .
You need to punish her . Make an example of her .
Whip her .
I can 't whip her .
Then she needs to leave this house .
I 'm not staying in our future home with a thief .
- Madeleine , let 's just .. - We have proof .
She needs to leave .
You won 't regret that , Sebastien .
I have to do it with our servants
all the time .
It 's not a nice thing to do
but it 's a necessary burden .
And it 's my favorite bracelet .
Look .
You said that you put your bracelets
on the night stand
before you went to breakfast .
That 's right .
Then how were you wearing it this morning ?
What do you mean ?
I remember you wearing
the bracelet at breakfast .
I specifically took note of it .
How was it supposedly taken
from your night stand when you already had it ?
What are you saying ...
You planted that bracelet in Linh 's room .
- Didn 't you ? - Of course I didn 't .
Why would you do such a thing ?
Because I know .
What do you know ?
Don 't try to deny it .
How could you ?
With a lowly housemaid ?
- I 'm not ashamed . - You 're not ashamed ?
You 're cheating on your fiancÃ ©
with a primitive , common whore and you 're not ashamed !
She 's not a whore !
You love her , don 't you ?
Sebastien , you 're sick .
You 're becoming one of them .
- I won 't stand for this .. - No , this is ..
This is proof why you need to leave here .
I 'm not leaving .
You are .
I mean it .
Leave .
Now !
Just you wait till I tell your family about this .
That you 've risked their good family name
on a common harlot .
Yeah . Go tell them .
Go tell all of Paris .
See if I care .
Linh .
Linh , listen ..
How could you believe her ?
I told her to leave .
She 's gone .
I 'm sorry .
Hit me .
Hit me again .
Harder . Harder .
Harder !
I want you to hurt me .
What was that ?
Oh , God !
Oh , no .
Hello ?
Oh , God ! Hello ?
Oh , God !
I , uh ..
I couldn 't see you there . What are you doing ?
Oh , God .
Hello ?
Why has the kitchen been rearranged ?
The pantry is completely out of order .
It was me .
I made those changes .
What ?
Linh has brought it upon herself to make changes to the household .
Who gave you the authority ?
Sebastien has .
You don 't need to be upset , Mrs. Han .
Linh has only been here for a few months .
She doesn 't know .
Nobody knows Sa-Cat like you do .
But I think it 'd be best to have ... a new vision
for the house .
No , thank you , captain .
Please , take it .
Mrs. Han ..
... Linh has displayed the hard work
and dedication I want for the future
of the Sa-Cat .
Do you have a problem
with taking her instruction ?
I do , Captain Laurent .
Then perhaps it might be best
to return to your home
to take care of your mother .
She needs you more than Sa-Cat
does right now .
Can I take you to the train station ?
No , thanks .
I can go by myself .
Mrs. Han .
I 'm sorry that it had to come to this .
I 'm sure this was your plan all along .
What do you mean ?
I know many girls ,
who would spread their legs to get ahead .
You 're no different .
I 'm the lady of the house now .
Don 't bother ever coming back .
Understood ?
You can pretend to be the lady of the house ,
but we all know who you really are .
You .
A lowly peasant .
Madame Camille .
Please !
I 've been a good servant to you all these years .
I 'm still an informant for the French .
I swear .
I didn 't betray you .
I swear I didn 't betray you .
The war has escalated and the French army
is worried about losing the Gulf of Tonkin .
I have to return to battle .
Now ?
Tomorrow .
I 've recovered from my injuries .
I must return to my post .
You mustn 't go back . You 'll be killed .
They 're ordering me back .
I have to fulfill my duty .
I 'm leaving in the morning .
Make the Captain a special dinner tonight .
He 's heading out in the morning .
As you wish , Ma 'am .
Don 't call me that .
What shall I call you then ?
A storm 's brewing .
An omen of things to come .
Where did you bury them ?
They 're in the woods !
Betrayer !
Don 't kill me !
Venison .
He 'll need a knife for the meat .
Don 't worry about the Captain .
In the end , it might be all for the best .
I promise I 'll return .
This has happened before .
You leaving someone here in Sa-Cat
while you were away at war .
It 's like ..
... history is repeating itself .
I 'll come back to you .
Sebastien .
You are mine !
No !
Stop haunting me !
You are mine !
Stop !
Stop haunting me !
Sebastien !
His blood was everywhere .
It was horrible .
And you didn 't hear anything in the night ?
No .
No one .
Just the ghost .
I saw her with my own eyes .
But why would the ghost of his dead wife
want to kill him ?
If she couldn 't have the Captain ...
then nobody else could have him .
We don 't have enough to keep you here
so we 're letting you go .
But we 'll need to interview you again ,
once everyone involved has been questioned .
Thank you .
Don 't go too far .
We 're still not done with you .
How did I do ?
Did the detective believe me ?
Hurry ! Hurry !
There they are !
Go get them !
Faster !
I know it was difficult for you going back ...
but they would have recognized me .
Drag him here !
Hurry UP !
Let us go !
They were trying to escape !
You know what we do to plantation workers who try to escape ?
You turned us in ?
You need to be more careful about who you talk to .
How could you ?
We trusted you !
Where are the two children ?
Where are they ?
Bastard !
Let 's start .
Get up !
Go ahead !
Ready ?
One .
Two .
Three !
We did this ...
for the workers .
She was still an informant for the French .
I 'm still an informant for the French army !
I didn 't betray .
He ordered the deaths of our parents .
He has to die .
We have to do this .
I can 't .
Forgive me .
No .
No !
Are you sure you know where our parents are ?
Mom and Dad would have been proud of you .
I didn 't recognize you at first ,
You haven 't changed much since you were little .
You and your brother were lucky enough to have escaped .
Your parents weren 't so lucky .
I 'm sorry about the Captain .
I 'm sure it wasn 't easy for you .
Why did you kill Madeleine ?
She was already leaving .
I didn 't kill her .
Then who did ?